Simon Meredith

Service Design

simon@lerefuge.co.uk +44 7825805466 www.lerefuge.co.uk Senior designer with experience in service and interaction design roles. Recently I led design for the new biodiversity net gain register and Apply for a divorce service in alpha and beta phases, designing end to end services, building and testing with the GOV.UK Prototype Kit. I've also led design in two discovery phases for HMCTS Tribunals and NHS England.

I'm used to designing complex services, these have included a new TV & Radio scheduling tool for BBC and a new app for Defra to record and manage UK fishing activity and quotas. I've worked on multiple public-facing products for the Government, the BBC and a tech start-up, being responsible for design, research and testing.

I'm confident in designing for responsive web and native apps. And used to working the different phases of a project from discovery, alpha through to beta build and live services.

Skills

User research, insight, interviews, audits, product analysis, process mapping workshop design & facilitation, user centred design, storyboards, wireframes, user flows, journey and service maps, hi + low fi prototyping, UI / visual design.

Tools: Sketch, Adobe CC, pen, paper, Figma, InVision, Miro, Mural, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, GOV.UK Prototyping Kit, GDS Design system, Agile working.

Experience

Cabinet Office - Service Design

July 2023 - November 2023 (Contract)

Implementation and testing of GOV.UK designs and interaction patterns for data focused Continuous Improvement Assessment tool, improving overall user experience, accessibility and usability.

Money and Pensions Service (Solirius) - Interaction Design

May 2023 - July 2023 (Contract)

Re-design of a suite of tools and calculators for MoneyHelper. Implementing new GOV.UK designs and interaction patterns and testing weekly with users.

Department for Culture, Media & Sport (Methods) - Service Design

March 2023 - April 2023 (Contract)

Customer journey mapping and user insight for a new internal digital, data and technology function.

NHS England (Olive Jar Digital) - Service Design

April 2022 - August 2022 (Contract)

Working with midwives, obstetricians and GP's to create user journey maps for maternity and child health across the NHS.

Natural England, Defra (Nomensa & RedRock) - Service Design

October 2021 - March 2022 (Contract)

Mapping of the service landscape, creating service blueprints and end-to-end user journeys based on user research, subject matter expert engagement and running insight and co-design sessions with policy, legal and business colleagues.

Resulting in an Alpha service assessment pass in March 2022.

Experience continued

The Charity Commision & Scope (Mace & Menter) - UX Consultancy

April 2021 - June 2021 (Contract)

Developing a series of new interaction patterns for the Scope website.

HMCTS (Transform UK) - Interaction Design

October 2020 - April 2021 (Contract)

Design an implementation of the new no-fault divorce legislation for the Apply for a divorce and End a civil partnership online services.

MMO, DEFRA & HMCTS (Transform UK) - Interaction Design

April 2019 - July 2019 & October 2019 - March 2020 (Multiple contracts)

Research, wireframes, user journeys, hi + low fi prototyping for app to record all fishing activity across the UK. Two discovery phases for 11 tribunals.

Legal Aid Agency, Ministry of Justice - Interaction Design

April 2018 - April 2019 (Contract)

Design, prototypes (GOV.UK Prototyping Kit) and testing for the new legal aid application service from discovery through to private beta.

BBC Internal Tools - UX Design

July 2017 - January 2018 (Contract)

All design for BBC's new TV and Radio scheduling tool supporting a team of 10 developers. Responsible for insight, design, prototyping and testing.

Encore Musicians - Head of Design

October 2016 - June 2017

Leading all UX and UI design across web and apps. Contributing to product roadmap and strategy. Leading research, insight and testing. Design of new enquiries form, payments/bookings system and update to visual identity.

BBC UX&D - Radio & Music, GEL, News, Homepage - UX Designer

May 2013 - October 2016

Music site re-structure, find a track, iPlayer Radio recommendations & favourites, App Store videos. New responsive grid and new design patterns.

Education

Manchester School of Architecture

2007 - 2010

BA HONS Architecture

Poole Grammar School

2000 - 2006

A-Levels - Art, Media, History A, A, C

GCSEs - 11 grades A to C